Guide to the Hermann Hagedorn Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Hermann Hagedorn papers
1898-1970
YCAL MSS 391
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
20
(46 boxes)
Collection contains correspondence, writings, clippings, and other materials documenting the life of author Hermann Hagedorn. Correspondence in the collection consists of letters to and from family, friends, other writers, publishers, scholars, and well-known political and cultural figures from the first half of the twentieth century. Noteworthy correspondents include Stephen Vincent Benét, Albert Einstein, Robert Frost, Percy MacKaye, Ezra Pound, Edwin Arlington Robinson, and Albert Schweitzer, as well as Theodore ("Teddy"), Franklin D., and Eleanor Roosevelt. Writings include drafts and research materials for articles, plays, poems, short stories, speeches, and biographical works. In addition, there are clippings on Hagedorn and reviews of his literary and biographical works. Other materials include medals, music, photographs, printed materials, and a scrapbook
Hagedorn, Hermann, 1882-1964
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Alta California Bookstore, 1966, with additional small gifts and purchases to 1978.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Hermann Hagedorn (1882-1964)
Hermann Hagedorn was born in New York City in 1882 and educated at Harvard University, the University of Berlin, and Columbia University. From 1909 to 1911 he was an instructor in English at Harvard. Hagedorn was a friend and biographer of Theodore Roosevelt and served as Secretary and Director of the Theodore Roosevelt Association from 1919 to 1957. Hagedorn died in Santa Barbara, California in 1964.
Scope and Contents
The Hermann Hagedorn papers contain correspondence, writings, clippings, and other materials documenting the life of poet and biographer Hermann Hagedorn. Correspondence in the collection consists of letters to and from family, friends, other writers, publishers, scholars, and well-known political and cultural figures from the first half of the twentieth century. Noteworthy correspondents include Stephen Vincent Benét, Albert Einstein, Robert Frost, Percy MacKaye, Ezra Pound, Edwin Arlington Robinson, and Albert Schweitzer, as well as Theodore ("Teddy"), Franklin D., and Eleanor Roosevelt. Writings include drafts and research materials for articles, plays, poems, short stories, speeches, and biographical works. In addition, there are clippings on Hagedorn and reviews of his literary and biographical works. Other materials include medals, music, photographs, printed materials, and a scrapbook.
The collection features material documenting Hagedorn's research on Theodore Roosevelt and his work with the Theodore Roosevelt Association.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: I. Correspondence, 1898-1970. II. Writings, 1900-1962. III. Clippings, 1906-1963. IV. Other Materials, 1900-1964.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Clippings (information artifacts); Photographic prints; Authors; Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1898-1943; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955; Frost, Robert, 1874-1963; Hagedorn, Hermann, 1882-1964; MacKaye, Percy, 1875-1956; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972; Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1869-1935; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919; Schweitzer, Albert, 1875-1965
- Correspondence, 1898-1970; Series I; 7.71; (19 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  Series I, Correspondence, contains correspondence with family, friends, writers, publishers, scholars, and well-known political and cultural figures from the first half of the twentieth century. Noteworthy correspondents include Stephen Vincent Benét, Albert Einstein, Robert Frost, Percy MacKaye, Ezra Pound, and Edwin Arlington Robinson, as well as Theodore ("Teddy"), Franklin D., and Eleanor Roosevelt. Larger files can be found for the subjects of Hagedorn's biographies: Theodore Roosevelt, E. A. Robinson, and Albert Schweitzer. Correspondence concerning Roosevelt and unsorted correspondence is located at the end of the alphabetical sequence.
  Folders may contain third-party correspondence and other materials, such as drafts of manuscripts and printed ephemera.
  - "A" General, 1914-1962 (Box 1)
  - Academy of American Poets, 1958-1960 (Box 1)
  - Adamic, Louis, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Adams, James Truslow, 1931-1936 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Sherman, 1956-1958 (Box 1)
  - Aldis, Mary, undated (Box 1)
  - Association Press, 1947-1951 (Box 1)
  - Austin, Mary, 1937 September 21 (Box 1)
  - Ayer, Charles F., 1927-1937 (Box 1)
  - "B" General, 1915-1962 (Box 1)
  - Baker, George Pierce, 1911-1935 (Box 1)
  - Barton, Bruce, 1948 April 9 (Box 1)
  - Bates, Katharine Lee, 1917 (Box 1)
  - Beach, Rex, 1916-1918 (Box 1)
  - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Berry College, 1946-1964 (Box 1)
  - Biggers, Earl D., undated (Box 1)
  - Bingham, Edfrid A., 1927-1929 (Box 1)
  - Binyon, Laurence, undated (Box 1)
  - Bliven, Bruce, undated (Box 2)
  - Blum, John M., 1951-1960 (Box 2)
  - Braithwaite, W. S., 1914-1959 (Box 2)
  - Branch, Anna H., 1914-1932 (Box 2)
  - Briggs, Le Baron R., 1904-1937 (Box 2)
  - Brookings, Mrs., 1934-1944 (Box 2)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1912-1948 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Alice, 1916 March 6 (Box 2)
  - Browne, Porter Emerson, 1917-1932 (Box 2)
  - Buck, Pearl S., 1942-1955 (Box 2)
  - Butler, Ellis Parker, 1918 (Box 2)
  - Bynner, Witter, 1904-1928 (Box 2)
  - "C" General, 1918-1964 (Box 2)
  - Calvert, Louis, 1916 (Box 2)
  - Canby, Henry S., 1937-1939 (Box 2)
  - Carman, Bliss, 1918-1926 (Box 2)
  - Century Association, 1936-1959 (Box 2)
  - Chambers, Robert W., 1918 October 26 (Box 2)
  - Chancellor, Paul, 1950-1960 (Box 2)
  - Charnwood, 1931-1940 (Box 2)
  - Ciardi, John, 1959 June 3 (Box 2)
  - Clemens, Cyril, 1936-1949 (Box 2)
  - Clifton, Chalmers, 1915-1916 (Box 2)
  - Coblentz, Stanton A., 1947 February 9 (Box 2)
  - Colcord, Lincoln, 1918 (Box 2)
  - Conant, Isabel Eiske, undated (Box 2)
  - Cousins, Norman, 1961-1964 (Box 2)
  - Cowl, Jane, undated (Box 2)
  - Cowles, Anna Roosevelt, 1917-1927 (Box 2)
  - "D" General, 1915-1963 (Box 3)
  - Damrosch, Walter, 1936-1941 (Box 3)
  - Danner, Sara K., 1951 (Box 3)
  - Day, John, Company, 1930-1964 (Box 3)
  - Derby, Ethel C. and Richard, 1918-1960 (Box 3)
  - Dodd, Lee Wilson, 1918-1926 (Box 3)
  - "E" General, 1916-1964 (Box 3)
  - Eastman, Max, 1954-1955 (Box 3)
  - Edwards, Deane, 1939-1963 (Box 3)
  - Einstein, Albert, 1916-1968 (Box 3)
    Scope and Contents
    Contains one letter from Einstein, dated 1950, and other correspondence acquired in a small 1968 purchase.
  - Erskine, John, 1925-1935 (Box 3)
  - "F" General, 1915-1963 (Box 3)
  - Ficke, A. D., 1936 September 6 (Box 3)
  - Fillmore, J. E., 1926-1951 (Box 3)
  - Fillmore, Louise & Parker, 1931-1950 (Box 3)
  - Finkelstein, Louis, 1942-1962 (Box 3)
  - Fletcher, Richmond K., 1940-1948 (Box 3)
  - Foster, Margaret, 1951-1952 (Box 3)
  - Francke, Kuno, 1918-1930 (Box 3)
  - Fraser, Laura Gardin, 1937-1964 (Box 3)
  - Frost, Lowell C., 1915-1959 (Box 3)
  - Frost, Robert, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "G" General, 1916-1964 (Box 4)
  - Garfield, James A., 1927-1963 (Box 4)
  - Garland, Hamlin, 1927-1960 (Box 4)
  - Geismar, Maxwell, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Gentry, Caroline, 1927-1935 (Box 4)
  - Ginn & Co., 1917-1918 (Box 4)
  - Goudge, Elizabeth, undated (Box 4)
  - Grew, Joseph C., 1946-1962 (Box 4)
  - Guiterman, Arthur, 1930-1943 (Box 4)
  - "H" General, 1914-1964 (Box 4)
  - Hagedorn family, 1927-1964 (Box 5)
  - Hagedorn, 1932-1958 (Box 5)
  - Hagedorn, Dorothy O., 1938-1961 (Box 5)
  - Hagedorn, Eric & Dorothea, 1946-1959 (Box 5)
  - Hagedorn, Hermann, 1925-1960 (Box 5)
  - Hagedorn, Mary, 1947-1959 (Box 5)
  - Hammond, Emily V., 1937-1960 (Box 6)
  - Hampden, Walter, 1916 June 20 (Box 6)
  - Hanna, A. J., 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - Harbaugh, W. H., 1959-1963 (Box 6)
  - Harcourt, Ellen, 1946-1960 (Box 6)
  - Harper & Brothers, 1918-1959 (Box 6)
  - Hart, Albert Bushnell, 1917-1931 (Box 6)
  - Harvard University, 1904-1949; 2 (Box 6)
  - Hays, Will H., 1918-1950 (Box 6)
  - Heider, Werner, 1937 (Box 6)
  - Hill School, 1899-1964; 2 (Box 6)
  - Hilton, James, 1935 November 19 (Box 6)
  - Holmes, John Haynes, 1931-1962 (Box 6)
  - House, Col. Edward M., 1931 (Box 6)
  - Howe, M. A. DeW., 1917-1958 (Box 6)
  - Hughes, Charles Evans, 1927 (Box 6)
  - Hunt, Edward Eyre, 1927-1948 (Box 6)
  - "I" General, 1916-1960 (Box 6)
  - "J" General, 1918-1961 (Box 6)
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood, 1918 July 8 (Box 6)
  - "K" General, 1917-1963 (Box 7)
  - Kantor, MacKinlay, 1963 April 26 (Box 7)
  - Keller, Deane, 1959-1960 (Box 7)
  - Kent, Barbara, 1930-1931 (Box 7)
  - Krock, Arthur, 1918-1934 (Box 7)
  - Krutch, Joseph Wood, 1959 (Box 7)
  - "L" General, 1915-1963 (Box 7)
  - Lambert, Alexander, 1919-1937 (Box 7)
  - Lamont, T. W., 1919-1947 (Box 7)
  - Lasky, Jesse L., 1926-1948 (Box 7)
  - Ledoux, Louis V., 1910-1938 (Box 7)
  - Lenalie, A., 1914-1922 (Box 7)
  - Lester, John A., 1915-1959 (Box 8)
  - Lindbergh, Charles A., 1970 January 19 (Box 8)
  - Linderman, Frank, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Lindsay, Howard, 1946-1960 (Box 8)
  - Lindsay, Vachel, 1917-1918; 2 (Box 8)
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1916-1960 (Box 8)
  - Little, Walter H., 1925-1931 (Box 8)
  - Lodge, H. C., 1918-1931 (Box 8)
  - Lohrke, Eugene, 1919-1931 (Box 8)
  - "M" General, 1913-1964 (Box 8)
  - Mabie, Hamilton W., 1914 October 25 (Box 8)
  - McCoy, Frank, 1930-1960 (Box 8)
  - MacDowell, Mrs. Edward, 1916-1955 (Box 8)
  - MacDowell Colony, 1916-1957 (Box 9)
  - McIntosh & Otis, Inc., 1940-1964 (Box 9)
  - MacKaye, Percy, 1910-1961; 3 (Box 9)
  - Macmillan, 1914-1960 (Box 9)
  - MacVeagh, Lincoln, 1919-1924 (Box 9)
  - Magee, John G., 1942-1946 (Box 9)
  - Manship, Paul, 1960-1962 (Box 9)
  - Marks, Josephine Peabody, 1909-1925 (Box 9)
  - Mason, Daniel Gregory, 1916-1938 (Box 9)
  - Maury, Magruder Gordon, 1931-1948 (Box 9)
  - Mayo, Katherine, 1932 (Box 9)
  - Meigs, John, 1904-1963; 2 (Box 9)
  - Merrill, Mrs. Elmer T., 1944-1947; 2 (Box 9)
  - Meynell, Alice & Francis, 1965 (Box 10)
  - Middlebury College, 1931-1935 (Box 10)
  - Monroe, Harriet, 1916 February 22 (Box 10)
  - Mumford, Lewis, 1954-1955 (Box 10)
  - "N" General, 1914-1961 (Box 10)
  - Neihardt, John G., 1957 (Box 10)
  - Nevins, Allan, 1943-1960 (Box 10)
  - New Music Press, Inc., 1930 (Box 10)
  - Noyes, Alfred, 1911-1947 (Box 10)
  - "O" General, 1917-1962 (Box 10)
  - Oboler, Arch, 1946 (Box 10)
  - O'Brian, John Lord, 1931-1964 (Box 10)
  - Outlook, 1914-1931 (Box 10)
  - "P" General, 1915-1962 (Box 10)
  - Pacific Coast Publishing Co., 1946-1962 (Box 10)
  - Parker, Horatio, 1918 (Box 10)
  - Perry, Bliss, 1925-1948 (Box 10)
  - Phelps, William Lyon, 1916 March 17 (Box 10)
  - Pinchot, Gifford, 1922-1946 (Box 10)
  - Price, Lucien, 1918-1963 (Box 10)
  - Pound, Ezra, undated (Box 10)
  - Pulsifer, Harold T., 1915-1949 (Box 10)
  - "Q" General, 1945 (Box 10)
  - "R" General, 1915-1963 (Box 11)
  - Ranck, Carty, 1915-1931 (Box 11)
  - Reynolds, John, 1949-1964 (Box 11)
  - Richards, Laura E., 1926-1940 (Box 11)
  - Richards, Rosalind, 1937-1949 (Box 11)
  - Robins, Margaret D. & Raymond, 1924-1937 (Box 11)
  - Robinson, Corinne (Roosevelt), 1917-1931 (Box 11)
  - Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1910-1934; 6 (Box 11)
  - Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1913-1959; 4 (Box 12)
  - Roosevelt, Archibald B., 1947-1962 (Box 12)
  - Roosevelt, Edith K., 1916-1945 (Box 12)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1936-1960 (Box 12)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor B., 1944-1959 (Box 12)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1930 (Box 12)
  - Roosevelt, Kermit, 1930-1937 (Box 12)
  - Roosevelt, Nicholas, 1927-1961 (Box 12)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1917-1948; 2 (Box 12)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore Jr., 1920-1940 (Box 12)
  - Root, Elihu, 1929-1936 (Box 12)
  - Rough Riders, 1926 (Box 12)
  - "S" General, 1914-1964 (Box 12)
  - "S" General, 1931-1961 (Box 13)
  - Schweitzer, Albert & Mrs., 1943-1964; 2 (Box 13)
  - Sedgwick, Ellery, 1915-1947 (Box 13)
  - Sheldon, Theodore, 1905-1961 (Box 13)
  - Sinclair, May, 1911-1912 (Box 13)
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1929-1945 (Box 13)
  - Smith, Chard Powers, 1961-1963 (Box 13)
  - Smith, H. Alexander, 1944-1960 (Box 13)
  - Smith, J. Andre, 1914-1917 (Box 13)
  - Stickney, Dorothy, 1927-1947 (Box 13)
  - Stimson, Henry L., 1931-1949 (Box 13)
  - Stratton, Leslie C., 1927-1964 (Box 13)
  - Straus, Oscar S., 1955-1964 (Box 13)
  - Street, Julian, 1916-1963 (Box 13)
  - Sullivan, Mark, 1921-1930 (Box 13)
  - Sweeney, Michael F., 1930-1935 (Box 13)
  - "T" General, 1916-1964 (Box 14)
  - Thompson, William Boyce, 1926-1933, undated; 2 (Box 14)
  - Torrence, Ridgely, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Towne, Charles Hanson, 1916-1940 (Box 14)
  - Toy, Nancy, 1914-1932 (Box 14)
  - Train, Arthur, 1939-1945 (Box 14)
  - "U" General, 1926-1963 (Box 14)
  - Underwood, John Curtis, undated (Box 14)
  - U. S. government, 1918-1964 (Box 14)
  - "V" General, 1918-1963 (Box 14)
  - Vail, R. W. G., 1926-1927 (Box 14)
  - Van Dyke, Henry, 1918 January 19 (Box 14)
  - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem, 1917-1960 (Box 14)
  - "W" General, 1916-1964 (Box 14)
  - Wagenknecht, Edward, 1957-1962 (Box 15)
  - Wallace, DeWitt, 1955-1961 (Box 15)
  - Wallach, Sidney, Associates, 1957-1964 (Box 15)
  - Washburn, Charles G., 1917-1927 (Box 15)
  - Wattles, Willard, 1917-1918 (Box 15)
  - Weldon, Hugh J., 1946-1959 (Box 15)
  - Wendell, Barrett, 1911-1918 (Box 15)
  - Westhoff, Gisela, 1926-1943 (Box 15)
  - Wheelock, John Hall, 1912-1953 (Box 15)
  - White, William Allen, 1929-1937 (Box 15)
  - Winston, John C., Co., 1927-1951 (Box 15)
  - Winterich, John T., 1960-1962 (Box 15)
  - Wood, Leonard, 1919-1960 (Box 15)
  - Woods, Marion (Meigs), 1941-1960 (Box 15)
  - "Y" General, 1918-1955 (Box 15)
  - Yorska, 1916, undated (Box 15)
  - "Z" General, 1947-1956 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence Concerning Roosevelt ("A" - "L"), 1919-1949; 11 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence Concerning Roosevelt ("M" - "Z"), 1913-1949; 9 (Box 17)
  - Unsorted correspondence and papers, 1931-1962; 10 (Box 18)
  - Unsorted correspondence and papers, 1898-1959; 4 (Box 19)
- Writings, 1900-1962; Series II; 5; (12 boxes)
  Arranged alphabetically by title (in quotations or italics), genre, or format.
  Series II, Writings, contains drafts and research materials for articles, plays, poems, short stories, speeches, and biographical works. Hagedorn wrote a number of books on Theodore ("Teddy") Roosevelt and served as Secretary and Director of the Theodore Roosevelt Association, and there are four boxes of materials relating to Roosevelt and the Association.
  - "American Vistas", 1924, undated (Box 20)
  - The Bomb that Fell on America, 1946, undated; 3 (Box 20)
  - "The Book of April Fools", undated (Box 20)
  - "The Boy in Armor: A Play for Boys", 1916 (Box 20)
  - "The Butter Paddle", undated (Box 20)
  - Combat at Midnight, 1940, undated (Box 20)
  - "The Delectable Forest", 1911 March 24; 2 (Box 21)
  - "Faces in the Dawn", 1913 (Box 21)
  - "The Fiddler", undated (Box 21)
  - "Fox, George - notes for a biography of", undated (Box 21)
  - The Great Maze, 1916, undated; 2 (Box 21)
    Includes draft with comments by E. A. Robinson
  - "Happy Eremite" articles, 1914-1918 (Box 21)
  - The Heart of Youth, 1915 (Box 22)
  - Journal, undated (Box 22)
  - "Leonard Wood", 1931 October 27 (Box 22)
  - "The Majesty of the Law", undated (Box 22)
  - "The Man Who Stopped War", undated (Box 22)
  - "Millenium", 1911 (Box 22)
  - "National Re-Dedication", 1958; 2 (Box 22)
  - "Notes on a Whirl Through Scotland", 1911 October 8 (Box 22)
  - Notebooks, 1904-1907; 5 (Box 23)
  - Outlines and Short Story plots, undated (Box 23)
  - Poems, 1914-1917, undated; 4 (Box 24)
  - Poems, 1914-1951, undated; 2 (Box 25)
  - Play (untitled), undated (Box 25)
  - "Prinz von Hamburg", 1913 (Box 25)
  - Roosevelt, 1900-1953, undated; 11 (Box 26)
  - Roosevelt, undated; 5 (Box 27)
    Includes drafts for "A Spirit in Man", "Fighting Fathers and Fighting Sons" and "Letters from Sagamore Hill"
  - Roosevelt, undated; 5 (Box 28)
    Includes drafts for "Resurrection of a Personality"
  - Theodore Roosevelt Association, 1919-1963; 8 (Box 29)
  - "A Search and a Finding", undated (Box 30)
  - "Schweitzer", undated (Box 30)
  - Speeches, 1914-1963, undated; 9 (Box 30)
  - Stories, 1942, undated; 3 (Box 31)
  - "Vigilantes" article, 1916, undated (Box 31)
  - "Washington" book, 1924-1925 (Box 31)
  - "While There Is Time", 1962; 2 (Box 31)
- Clippings, 1906-1963; Series III; 3.34; (9 boxes)
  Arranged alphabetically by folder heading.
  Series III, Clippings, contains clippings of general interest on Hermann Hagedorn and reviews of his literary and biographical works.
  Unsorted clippings are listed at the end of the alphabetical sequence.
  - "The Americanism of Theodore Roosevelt", 1923 (Box 32)
  - "Barbara Picks a Husband", 1918; 2 (Box 32)
  - "The Bomb that Fell on America", undated (Box 32)
  - "Book of Courage", 1929-1936 (Box 32)
  - "The Boy's Life of Roosevelt", 1918-1920 (Box 32)
  - "Combat at Midnight", undated (Box 32)
  - "The Delectable Forest", 1912-1916 (Box 32)
  - "Edwin Arlington Robinson", 1936-1938; 2 (Box 32)
  - "Faces in the Dawn", 1914-1915; 2 (Box 32)
  - "The Great Maze" and "The Heart of Youth", 1915-1918; 2 (Box 32)
  - Hermann Hagedorn and family, 1921-1960; 5 (Box 33)
  - Harvard University, 1925-1936 (Box 33)
  - "Hymn of Free People's Triumphant", 1918-1919 (Box 33)
  - "Ladders Through the Blue", 1925-1926 (Box 33)
  - "Leonard Wood", 1931, undated (Box 33)
  - "The Magnate" (William B. Thompson), 1935-1936 (Box 33)
  - "Makers of Madness", 1914-1921; 2 (Box 33)
  - "Old Four Eyes", 1958 (Box 33)
  - "Poems and Ballads", 1912-1919 (Box 33)
  - "Prophet in the Wilderness", 1947 (Box 33)
  - "Prophet of Unity", 1924-1925 (Box 33)
  - "Robert S. Brookings", 1936-1937; 2 (Box 34)
  - "Roosevelt in the Bad Lands", 1922-1930; 2 (Box 34)
  - "The Rough Riders", 1925-1928; 4 (Box 34)
  - "Sunward I've Climbed", 1942 (Box 34)
  - "The Ten Dreams of Zach Peters", 1927 (Box 34)
  - Theodore Roosevelt, 1924-1957 (Box 34)
  - The Theodore Roosevelt House, 1924-1956 (Box 34)
  - The Theodore Roosevelt Treasury, 1957 (Box 34)
  - "A Troop of the Guard", 1909 (Box 34)
  - "Victory", 1906 (Box 34)
  - "Where Do You Stand?", 1917-1918; 2 (Box 34)
  - "While There is Time", 1962 (Box 34)
  - Miscellaneous, 1917-1936; 2 (Box 34)
  - Unsorted clippings, 1912-1922; 9 (Box 35)
  - Unsorted clippings, 1911-1963; 7 (Box 36)
  - Unsorted clippings, 1954-1955; 8 (Box 37)
  - Unsorted clippings, 1907-1943; 8 (Box 38)
  - Unsorted clippings, 1916-1961; 10 (Box 39)
  - Unsorted clippings, 1914-1931; 4 (Box 40)
- Other Material, 1900-1964; Series IV; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Arranged alphabetically by material type.
  Series IV, Other Materials, contains commemorative materials such as medals and printed ephemera, music, photographs, other printed materials, and a scrapbook.
  - Button, undated (Box 41)
  - Medals and medallions, undated; 15 (Box 41)
  - Medals and medallions, undated; 3 (Box 42)
  - Music scores, with lyrics by Hagedorn, 1937, undated
  - Photograph albums, 1900-1913
  - "Photographs for Thompson Booth", undated (Box 42)
  - Printed ephemera, 1917-1954; 8 (Box 42)
  - Printed and other materials, 1908-1964, undated; 9 (Box 43)
  - Scrapbook, 1909-1911
- Oversize, 2.75; (3 boxes)
  - Music scores, with lyrics by Hagedorn (In Series IV), 1937, undated; 15 (Box 44)
  - Photographs albums (In Series IV), 1900-1913; 2 (Box 45)
  - Printed certificate (In Series IV), 1920 September 9 (Box 46)
  - Scrapbook (In Series IV), 1909-1911 (Box 46)